One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
Finale
الختام
What? They rushed off the island?
ماذا؟ لقد خرجوا بسرعة من الجزيرة؟
Yes. We couldn't even give them our gift.
.أجل، لم نستطع إعطاءهم عربون شكرنا حتى
What a pity...
...كم هذا محبط
I wonder if they even realize how grateful we are for what they did.
أتساءل إن كانوا يدركون حتى مدى امتنانا لما فعلوه من أجلنا
Indeed. They still don't grasp our feelings.
.بالضبط. لا يدركون مشاعرنا حقًّا
It's not fair, Aisa...
...هذا غير عادل يا آيسا
You're the only one who got to say goodbye to them.
...إنك الوحيدة التي استطاعت توديعهم
They can't stop talking about how we let our saviors run away.
الجميع في حالة صخب لأنّنا .تركنا منقذينا يلوذون بالفرار
But Luffy and the others told me not to tell anyone.
لكن لوفي والبقيّة أخبروني .أن أبقي الأمر سرًّا عن الجميع
Hey Raki, did you know that Luffy's body stretches?!
بالمناسبة يا راكي، هل تعلمين أنّ جسد لوفي يتمدّد؟
He'd be like, "Gum-Gum Pistol!"
«!يقول مثلًا: «غومو غومو نو: بيستول
Hey, Aisa, hold still!
!مهلًا يا آيسا، لا تتحركي
Who knew there was a strong warrior in the Blue Sea, too?!
من كان يعلم أن هنالك محارب شديد !البأس مثله في البحر الأزرق أيضًا؟
I wanna be like him, like "Gum-Gum...!"
أريد أن أصبح مثله وأؤدي !مثل مهارات المطّاط خاصته
Aisa...
...آيسا
Let's just give it a trim for today. You should let your hair grow out.
.لنشذّب شعرك فحسب اليوم. دعيه ينمو
I'm sure it'll look good on you. You're a girl, so you should look cute.
.أنا واثقة أنّه سيبدو جيّدًا عليك .أنت فتاة، لذا عليك أن تبدين ظريفة
Cute?! Me?!
ظريفة؟! أنا؟
That's right!
!هذا صحيح
Now that there's no need for you kids to carry weapons...
بما أن الأطفال مثلكِ ليس .عليهم حمل الأسلحة بعد الآن
you can live freely, like people in the sky should.
.وتعيشين كما يعيش الناس في السماء، بكل حريةٍ
You sure are ladylike today!
.أنت تتصرّفين كآنسةٍ اليومَ حقًّا
Now, hold still, Aisa!
!أخبرتك ألاّ تتحرّكي يا آيسا
Ladylike Raki!
!راكي الآنسة
Aisa!
!آيسا
Great Warrior Kalgara...
...المحارب العظيم كالغارا
We were told that the sacred duty of the Shandians had been fulfilled.
.سمعنا أنّ دور شعب شانديا قد أُنجز
And I'm sure your best friend heard your wish as well.
وأنا واثق أنّ أمنيّتك وصلت .إلى صديقك المقرّب أيضًا
Future generations will no longer need to shed their blood.
ما عدنا بحاجة لجعل الأجيال .القادمة تسفك الدماء
Our fight may be over... but we will never lose our pride!
...قد يكون قتالنا قد انقضى !ولكننا لن نسخر فخرنا
So please continue to watch over us.
.لذا، تابع الاعتناء بنا رجاءً
We swear to always keep the Light of Shandora shining!
!نقسم أنّنا لن ندع نار شاندورا تخمد ثانيةً
I am merely the Sky Knight, a freelance mercenary.
أنا فارس السماء، جنديّ .مستقلّ قابل للتعيين
You are far better suited for it.
،أنت أنسب مني بكثير
This city belonged to your people from the start.
.فهذه المدينة تنتمي لشعبك في الأصل
What's this now?
ماذا تقول الآن؟
That's not a good reason.
.هذا ليس سببًا وجيهًا
I think this battle taught us all the hard truth...
أظنّ أنّ هذه المعركة جعلت ...الجميع يُدركون الحقيقة المرّة
that no one can claim ownership of vearth.
.وهي أنّ لا أحد يمكنه ادعاء ملكية فيرث...
The title of "god" provides strength.
،الإله هو داعمُنا
The name of the land is Skypiea. The name of the city is Shandora.
.اسم البلاد سكايبيا .اسم المدينة شاندورا
The only person who can unify them is you,
،والوحيد الذي يمكنه توحيدهما هو أنت
the one who's always anguished over this land's never-ending war.
الذي استمرّ في معاناته بسبب .المعركة في هذه البلاد
Sky Knight Gan Fall...
...يا فارس السماء غان فول
I ask you to take the seat of god once more
،أطلب منك أن تعتلي عرش الإله ثانيةً
and give this ailing nation the strength to heal.
.وتدعم هذه البلاد التي ما زال جرحها عميقًا
We'd like you to, as well!
!نطلب ذلك منك أيضًا
Lord Gan Fall!
!غان فول-ساما
As long as it's you, we're on board too!
!إن كان أنت، فنحن قابلون
Yeah!
!نعم
Gan Fall!
!غان فول
God!
!يا إلهنا
We need you!
!نحن بحاجتك
Alas...
...صدقًا
Just when I thought I could finally grow pumpkins in peace...
تمامًا عندما اعتقدت أنّي أستطيع ...الاستمتاع بزراعة اليقطين
Lower Skypiea, the White Sea
البحر الأبيض طبقة سكايبيا السفلى
Everyone! We can see it now!
!يا رفاق! يمكننا رؤيتها الآن
Take a look ahead! It's Cloud End!
!انظروا إلى الأمام رجاءً !إنها نهاية السحاب
Ah! Lemme see!
!لنرَ
We got here sooner than I thought.
.وصلنا إلى هنا أسرع ممّا ظننت
Do we have to leave already?
أسنغادر بهذه السرعة حقًّا...؟
Yeah, now that we're heading back, I don't want to say goodbye.
،فعلًا، بما أنّنا على وشك العودة .أعترف أنّني لا أريد المغادرة
It's time to say farewell to this pure white sea.
حان الوقت لتوديع هذا .البحر الأبيض النّاصع
The sky island was fun... but it was scary, too.
...كانت جزيرة السماء مسلّية .مع أنّها كانت مخيفة أيضًا
So there's a milky road through there that heads straight down to the Blue Sea, huh?
فور أن نعبر تلك البوّابة، سنهبط مباشرةً إلى البحر الأزرق عبر الطريق السحابيّ إذًا؟
I wonder if we'll ever visit the sky island again...
أتساءل إن كان في وسعنا زيارة ...جزيرة السماء ثانيةً
Maybe, maybe not.
.يصعب الجزم في ذلك
Well then, everyone! I'm sorry, but we'll say goodbye here!
!حسنٌ جميعًا! آسف! سنودّعكم هنا
Please take care, everyone!
!اعتنوا بأنفسكم رجاءً يا رفاق
Thanks for seeing us off!
!شكرًا على توديعنا
Conis! Take care of yourself!
!كونيس-تشان! اعتني بنفسك جيّدًا
Send our regards to the others, too!
!بلّغي التحيّة للبقيّة
See you!
!إلى اللقاء
Thanks for everything!
!شكرًا على كلّ شيء
No! We should be thanking you!
!كلاّ، بل نحن من علينا شكركم
I'll never forget you all!
!لن ننساكم أبدًا
Conis, old guy, and fluff ball! You all take care!
!كونيس والعمّ والأبيض الصغير !اعتنوا بأنفسكم
– Yeah!
!أجل
Now, furl the sails immediately and hold on tight to the ship!
والآن، افردوا الأشرعة فورًا !وتشبثوا جيّدًا بالسفينة
Alright! Let's do as he says!
!حسنٌ! افعلوا كما قال العمّ
Sounds like it's gonna go pretty fast!
!يبدو أنّها ستسير بسرعة كبيرة
Yeah, we're sliding 7,000 meters down! Hurry!
نعم، سنتزحلق من ارتفاع 7,000 متر !بعد كل شيء! سارعوا
– Okay!
!حسنًا
Wh-What?! Huh?!
!مـ-ماذا؟! ماذا؟
He says, "Don't forget about me."
«قال: «لا تنسوني
Oh... It's that south bird we brought to the sky with us.
صحيح... إنه طائر الجنوب .الذي أحضرناه إلى السماء معنا
Okay, Captain!
،حسنًا أيها القبطان
We got the log for the next island!
!لقد سجّلنا الجزيرة الجديدة
Alright! Once we get back down, we'll start a brand new adventure!
،أجل، صحيح! فور أن نهبط من هنا !سنشرع في مغامرة جديدة
You ready, guys?!
!أيها الرفاق! هل أنتم مستعدّون؟
We're going back to the Blue Sea!
!سنعود إلى البحر الأزرق
– Yeah!
!أجل
Everyone! Be careful while dropping!
!يا رفاق! احذروا وأنتم تهبطون
– Dropping?
ونحن نهبط؟
Heso!
!هيسو
Here we go! The sky island's famous octoballoon!
ها نحن أولاء! البالون الأخطبوط !الشهير في جزيرة السماء
An octopus!
!أخطبوط
You son of a...!
...يا ابن الـ
O-Ouch...
...مـ-مؤلم
Wh-Wh-What the...?!
!مـ-مـ-مـ-ماذا؟! ما الذي...؟
Hey, look! This is so cool!
!انظروا! هذا رائع حقًّا
What the hell is this?!
!ما هذا بالضبط؟
It's a balloon!
!إنه بالون
This is fun!
!هذا شيّق
We've slowed down!
!لقد أبطأنا
I... I thought that I was finally gonna go to the netherworld.
.خلتُ... خلتُ أنّني سأموت أخيرًا
Ring it! Let the ringing of the bell bid farewell to the saviors of this land!
اقرعوه! ودّعوا منقذي هذه !البلاد بقرع الجرس
Heso!
!هيسو
Luffy! Let's meet again!
!لوفي! لنلتقِ ثانيةً
Don't be a stranger!
!تعالوا لزيارتنا مجدّدًا
Thank you!
!شكرًا لكم
Safe travels back to the Blue Sea!
!عودوا إلى البحر الأزرق بأمان
When you cast your gaze toward the sky...
.عندما تنظرون إلى الأعلى، ترون السماء
Is it real, or is it but a dream, this God Land above the clouds?
هل أرض الإله في السحب حلم أم حقيقة؟
Ten thousand meters high in the sky...
...على ارتفاع 10,000 متر في السماء
If you listen closely, you can hear the sound of a bell.
.إن أصغيتم جيّدًا، يمكنكم أن تسمعوا صوت الجرس
It rings today. And it will ring again tomorrow.
.إنه يُقرع اليوم، ولسوف يُقرع غدًا
The echoing sound of the bell in the sky
صوت الجرس الذي يتردّد صداه في السماء
sings of the triumph of this wandering land...
...يمجّد ويغنّي عن الأرض المتجوّلة
This is cool!
!هذا رائع
Yeah! This is great!
!أجل! هذا عظيم
You're calling off the search?!
!ستلغي البحث؟
It's only natural, right?! The City of Gold was in the sky.
أليس هذا طبيعيّ؟! مدينة .الذهب موجودة في السماء
We won't find anything at the bottom of the sea.
.لن نعثر على أيّ شيء في قعر البحر
This is the end.
.هذه النّهاية
There's no point in staying here.
.لا سبب يدعونا للبقاء هنا
Boss...
...أيّها العجوز
I sincerely thank you all... for joining me in pursuit of my dream all these years.
أشكركم جميعًا حقًّا على الانضمام لي .في سعيي لتحقيق حلمي لسنوات
What are you saying...?
ماذا تقول...؟
Don't treat us like strangers...
...لا تعاملنا كالغرباء
Well then, gentlemen!
!أخبراني
What sort of romantic adventure shall we go after next?!
!أيّ مغامرات رومانسية نسعى إليها تاليًا؟
We'll follow you to the ends of the world, boss!
!سنتبعك حتى أقاصي الأرض أيّها العجوز
Gold! Gold! Gold! Gold! Gold!
!ذهب! ذهب! ذهب! ذهب! ذهب
We're finally super rich! What're we gonna buy?!
!أصبحنا فاحشي الثراء أخيرًا! ماذا نشتري؟
What about a huge bronze statue?!
!ما رأيكم بشراء تمثال برونزيّ؟
You moron! Why would you trade gold for bronze?!
أيّها الأحمق! ما المغزى من !استبدال الذهب بالبرونز؟
We should stock up on cannons!
!علينا زيادة أعداد المدافع
Let's buy ten of them! Ten!
!لنشترِ عشرة منها! عشرة
Nami! I want a refrigerator with a lock!
!نامي-سان! أريد ثلاّجة قابلة للقفل
Don't be stupid! What're we gonna do when we get hungry?! I object!
لا تتغابَ! ماذا سنفعل !عندما نجوع؟! أعارض
I... I... I want you to buy me some books!
!أنا... أنا... أريدك أن تشتري لي بعض الكتب
I wanna read medical books from other countries!
!أريد قراءة كتب طبيّة من بلدان أخرى
That's why we should buy it, dumbass!
!لهذا علينا أن نشتريها أيّها الأبله
Now hold on just a second, you guys!
!انتظروا لحظة يا رفاق
We'll split the treasure once we get back down, okay?
سنتقاسم الذهب فور أن نهبط، مفهوم؟
Please buy books for me!
!اشتري لي كتبًا رجاءً
If we spend our money willy-nilly, we'll end up wasting it all.
إن اشترينا ما تودّون، أشعر .أنّنا لن نستفيد من شيء
The sun's completely set now.
.غربت الشمس تمامًا الآن
It's a nice view, though.
.إن غروبها جميلٌ حقًّا
Yeah, you're right.
.نعم، معك حقّ
It's freezing...!
!...بارد
Nami! Robin! Are you okay?
نامي-سان! روبين-تشان! هل أنتما بخير؟
That startled me!
!أفزعني ذلك
The octopus suddenly shrank all the way!
!لقد تقلّص الأخطبوط بشكلٍ كامل فجأةً
Maybe it was an air leak.
أتساءل إن تسرّب الهواء
What the heck happened?!
!ماذا حدث بحق؟
Well, we somehow made it down... without dying.
.ولكننا هبطنا بأعجوبة... دون أن نهلك
Thanks a bunch!
!شكرًا لك
Still...
...مع ذلك
we really went to an incredible place, didn't we?
ذهبنا إلى مكان لا يصدق حقًّا، أليس كذلك؟
Now that we're down here, it seems so far away.
.بما أنّنا سقطنا، بات بعيدًا جدًّا في الأعلى
It's like we were dreaming.
.وكأنّنا كنّا نحلم
It's a dream land. I wonder if we can go visit again some day.
إنها أرض أحلام، أتساءل إن كان بمقدورنا .الذهاب لزيارتها ثانيةً يومًا
You might be able to get closer if you die.
.ربما تقترب من زيارتها إن مُت
Zoro, do you really think you'll be allowed into heaven?
يا زورو، أتظنّ أن بإمكانك الذهاب إلى الجنة حقًّا؟
Shut it!
!يا نذل
At any rate, things have calmed down.
.حسنٌ، هدأتِ الأمور الآن
I'll make coffee or something.
.سأعدّ قهوةً أو ما شابه
Better yet, make us some dinner, Sanji!
!أفضّل تناول العشاء يا سانجي
Yeah, yeah, I'll get right on it. Just sit tight and have some coffee.
،سأبادر في إعداده فورًا !لذا اشرب قهوةً الآن وانتظر
It's pirate loot, so we'll divide it equally!
،إنه كنز قراصنة !لذلك سيُقسم بالتساوي
We each get some?!
!سيقسم علينا جميعًا؟
Naturally.
.هذا أكيد
I've been waiting for this!
!كنتُ بانتظار هذا
I'm gonna buy a bronze statue!
!سأشتري تمثالًا برونزيًّا لي
Yeah! Can I buy books?!
!أجل! هل يمكننا شراء كتب؟
New pots, frying pans, silverware, and giant mousetraps...
،نحتاج لقدور ومقالٍ جديدة ...وأواني مائدة وفخاخ فئران
That leaves a crapload left over!
!وما زلت أحتاج للكثير رغم ذلك
I could drink all I want!
!سيكون بوسعي الشرب كما أشاء
First, 80 percent goes to my stash!
!أوّلاً، ستكون 80% منه لمدّخراتي
– Hold on a second!
!مهلًا لحظة
Just kidding.
.أمزح فحسب
Obviously! You can't have a public secret stash!
بالطبع! لا يمكنك امتلاك مدّخرات !سرّيّة بشكل علنيّ هكذا
By "stash," I mean our repair fund for the ship!
عندما قلت مدّخرات، قصدت المال !الّذي سنخصّصه لإصلاح السّفينة
The ship? You mean Merry?
السّفينة؟ أتقصدين ميري؟
That's right. The Going Merry is what brought us all this way.
هذا صحيح. غوينغ ميري هي ما .أحضرنا إلى حيث نحن الآن
Come to think of it,
،بالتفكير في الأمر
she's been our ride across the seas ever since my village in the East Blue...
حملتنا على متنها عبر البحار مُذ كنّا ...في قريتي في الأزرق الشّرقيّ
She's done so much for us, but now she's all beat up.
،قامت بالكثير من أجلنا .لكنّها حالتها سيئة الآن
Good idea! The Great Repair of the Going Merry!
!فكرة جيّدة! عملية إصلاح غوينغ ميري العظيمة
I'm all for it!
!أنا موافق تمامًا
Alright, dig in.
حسنٌ، تفضلوا
Yeah, come to think of it, Usopp's cheap repairs are just about at their limit.
صحيح. تكاد إصلاحات أوسوبّ .الرّخيصة تصبح غير نافعة
Hey, I'm just a marksman, you know!
!ضع في حسبانك أنّني قنّاص
Yeah. We should go to a real shipyard and have real shipwrights fix it for us.
،نعم. علينا الذّهاب إلى حوض إصلاح سفنٍ حقيقيّ .ونجعل سفّانًا حقيقيًّا يصلحها لنا
People can fix ships better than Usopp?
هنالك أشخاص أفضل من أوسوب في إصلاح السّفن؟
We have to fix her up properly from time to time,
،يجب أحيانًا أنّ نكون حذرين أكثر
or we'll pay for it later!
!وإلاّ دفعنا الثمن لاحقًا
Alright, it's decided!
!حسنًا، اتُّخذ القرار
Let's add a shipwright to our crew!
!لنضمّ سفّان لطاقمنا
We still have a long way to go!
!ما زالت رحلتنا في بدايتها فحسب
We need someone with those skills anyway.
...نحتاج لتلك المهارات على كلّ حال
Merry is our home!
!ميري هي منزلنا
Our life!
!حياتنا
Let's find a shipwright who can keep her safe!
!لنجد سفّانًا بإمكانه الحفاظ على سلامتها
There he goes again...
...ها قد بدأ ثانية
Yeah, on rare occasion, he really hits the nail on the head.
نعم، يدخل صلب الموضوع .مباشرة في أحيانٍ نادرة
That'd be perfect! Let's do it!
!تلك أفضل طريقة! لنفعل بذلك
Okay, then that's the plan!
!حسنًا، تلك هي الخطّة إذًا
I hope we find someone good!
!آمل أن نجد سفّانًا جيّدًا
And we need a musician, too!
!ونحتاج لموسيقيّ أيضًا
No, we really don't.
.لا، انس ذلك
What's all the ruckus?!
!ما كل هذه الجلبة؟
Run!
!اهربوا
Quit pushing! W-We gotta stay away from 'em!
!كفّ عن دفعي! عـ-علينا الابتعاد عنهم
A falling out?!
!شجار؟
Bellamy!
!بيلامي
Sarquiss!
!ساركيس
Please! Make him stop!
!أوقفوه رجاءً
Please! Just stop it! Why are you doing this...?!
!توقف رجاءً! لِمَ تفعل هذا...؟
What's happening?!
!ما الذي يجري؟
Sarquiss is the one begging to stop?
!ساركيس بعينه في مأزق
Why? Why, you ask?
لماذا؟ هل سألتني لماذا؟
Sarquiss... Bellamy...
...ساركيس... بيلامي
It's because you disrespected my flag, of course.
لأنّكم لطّختم رمزي، لا سبب غير هذا
"Does the sky island exist or not?"
«هل جزيرة السماء موجودة أم لا؟»
"Is the City of Gold real or not?"
«هل مدينة الذهب حقيقيّة أم لا؟»
I couldn't care less about any of that.
.لا ألقي بالًا لأيّ من ذلك
"Pit belief against belief to gain control over others."
عليك أن تتلاعب بالنّاس عن طريق .استغلال الآراء المختلفة
That's what I told you...
...هذا ما أخبرتك به
wasn't it, Bellamy?
أليس كذلك يا بيلامي؟...
That's... Donquixote Doflamingo!
!ذلك... دونكيهوتي دوفلامينغو
He's one of the Seven Warlords of the Sea!
!إنه أحد الشيتشيبوكاي
His bounty used to be over 300 million!
وكانت على رأسه مكافأة !أكبر من 300 مليون
What's a guy like him doing here?!
!ما الذي يفعله شخص مثله هنا؟
I don't need useless punks like you serving under me...
لا حاجة لي بسفلة عديمي نفع ...أمثالكم يخدمونني
Crap! My body's moving on its own!
!تبًّا! جسدي يتحرّك من نفسه
Stop! Please, don't...!
!...توقف! اعتقنا رجاءً
No!
!كلا
Bellamy!
!بيلامي
G-Give me...
...ا-امنحني
Give me one more chance...!
!...امنحني فرصة أخرى رجاءً
I'll... We'll be your loyal followers!
!أنا... نحن... سنتبعك بإخلاص
Bellamy!
!بيلامي
No more, Bellamy!
!يكفي يا بيلامي
Yes, I lost, but I never went against your principles!
!نعم، خسرتُ حقًّا، لكنّي لم أنتهك مبادءك مطلقًا
I swear on your flag!
!أقسم على رمزك
This is just my way of doing things!
!هذه طريقتي في القيام بالأمور فحسب
We couldn't just run him off!
،ما كان لنا أن نطردهم فحسب
He would've reached you someday!
!وإلاّ سيصل لك يومًا
How very touching, O faithful subordinate of mine.
.هذا مؤثّر جدًّا يا تابعي المطيع
That's what I like about you, Bellamy.
.هذا ما أحبه فيك يا بيلامي
A new era is just around the corner. Do as you wish.
.إنّ عصرًا جديدًا على الأبواب. فافعل ما شئت
However... I don't need you anymore.
.لكن... ما عدتُ بحاجة لك
Doflamingo!
!دوفلامينغو
He just took out a notorious rookie worth 55 million!
،قضى على شائن السمعة بيلامي ،ناشئٌ مكافأته 55 مليون
It was child's play to him!
!وكأنّه نكرة
It's finally beginning!
!لقد بدأ أخيرًا
You'd better be prepared!
!من الأفضل أن تستعدّوا
A world where only true pirates can survive is drawing near!
قد اقترب العالم الذي لا ينجو فيه !إلاّ القراصنة الحقيقيّون
The powerless among you— run while you can!
!أمّا الضعاف منكم لينفذوا بحياتهم
With the inevitable tides of time,
قريبًا، سيمحي مدّ الوقت كلّ شيء
a new era of champions will soon be upon us!
!وسيبدأ عصر جديد من الأبطال